VINCENT SANDERS

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER SPECIALIZING IN JAVASCRIPT, REACT AND NODE

CONTACT

- vincesanders@hotmail.com
- github.com/vincesanders
- www.vincent-sanders.com

PROFILE

Reliable, quick-learning and extremely motivated software engineer hoping to leverage my skills, diverse experience and passion to an organization in the Kansas City area. With teaching and international experience, I am accustomed to performing under pressure with tight deadlines.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

FRONT-END

JavaScript, React, Redux, Context API, Axios, jQuery, HTML, CSS/LESS/SCSS

BACK-END

Node, Express. Knex, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Java

OTHER

Git & GitHub collaboration Yarn, npm Heroku Wordpress Jest, Supertest (testing)

EDUCATION

LAMBDA SCHOOL

Oct 2019 - Present

Full-stack web development Computer Science

UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL MISSOURI

Bachelor's Degree, Music Technology Graduated with honors Two years of **computer science** courses Founded and Chaired UCM chapter of the Audio engineering Society

PROJECTS

THE QUEUE

Project Lead / Back-End Architect

The Queue is a ticket and issue tracking application that allows students to escalate concerns and receive help.

- Led the team, delegated tasks and oversaw and reviewed Git merges and site deployments.
- Built the back-end server and database under a strict deadline to allow the front-end to immediately build without dummy data.
- Utilized end-to-end testing to develop API endpoints in a test-driven environment.

AIRPRICE

Front-End Architect

AirPrice uses historical booking data to predict the optimal price for an AirBnB in Berlin.

- Led the front-end team in a cross-functional project.
- Collaborated with an international team of data science and machine learning engineers.
- Delegated tasks and supervised all Git merges to the development and master branches.
- Implemented the application's state management (Redux), communication with the back-end and DS servers, and all business logic.

SPIDER.GRAPH

Front-End Engineer

Spider. Graph allows a user to create dynamic radar graphs using an intuitive and responsive user interface.

- Collaborated with a team of six engineers to deliver a proof-ofconcept build backed by a stake-holder.
- Thrived in a fast-paced high-stakes environment to Build out the entire application in a week.

EXPERIENCE

WEBSITE COORDINATOR

The Association of Japan Exchange and Teaching (AJET) | Jul 2018 - Jul 2019

As a website coordinator, I worked mainly in the WordPress ecosystem. I managed content and website support. I used JavaScript, jQuery, HTML and CSS to create custom components and plug-ins.

ENGLISH TEACHER

Shimane Board of Education | Jul 2015 - Jul 2019

Developed original curriculum based on current educational theory. Led the English club, focusing on practicing English and learning about other cultures. Planned and implemented activities and outreach with the local community. Built many applications centered around classroom instruction in Java.